

Mattia Filippo De Luca

Product Manager | Product Owner

Email: info@selfrules.org LinkedIn: /in/selfrules

GitHub: /Selfrules

Website: selfrules.org

I am Mattia, a visionary Product Management expert and a master in the art of Product Ownership. I stand out for my talent in bringing complex projects to life, navigating through challenges with curiosity and determination, all with the goal of continuously improving my skills in this fascinating field. I create product symphonies that enchant users while staying upto-date on the latest trends and technologies. Experience has made me a tireless traveler in the vast universe of product management, I believe in my power to shape successful stars in the product firmament and contribute to the realization of the organization's goals.

Work Experience

Product Owner

ActiveProspect

January 2023 - May 2023

As **Product Owner** at ActiveProspect, I led the evolution of the *LeadsBridge* product, coordinating customer requirements, quality and delivery time. I worked closely with the *Development and UX/UI* teams, modeling *User Stories*, managing feature requests, and providing continuous feedback to improve the product. I acted as the main point of contact for *stakeholders*, managing communication and ensuring that the product met the needs of customers and partners.

Partners: Facebook, Google, Linkedin, TikTok

Product Owner

LeadsBridge

January 2021 - December 2022

In my role as **Product Owner** at *LeadsBridge*, I translated visions into concrete strategies, driving the product to new horizons. I coordinated product development with *business goals*,, embracing the *Agile* philosophy and integrating the *Scrum* framework. I managed the full product lifecycle, from ideation to launch, and kept the team focused on *value creation*, product adoption, customer retention, and reducing churn.

Partners: Facebook, Google, Linkedin, TikTok

Design and Development

January 2019 - January 2021

I hereby consent to the processing of my personal data contained in my application for the purpose of the recruitment process.

FLOWING

As a **Design and Development** professional at *FLOWING*, I operated as an architect of ideas, *shaping the backlog* according to business objectives and creating *user stories* to guide product development. I worked to remove obstacles, fostering an environment conducive to team productivity and building *positive relationships* with the product owner and external team members.

Day by Day: JavaScript, AngularJS, SASS, Sketch, Trello, Github

Ux/Ui Designer

October 2016 - January 2019

e-xtrategy

In my role as **UX and UI Designer** at *e-xtrategy*, I developed *simple*, *attractive* and *engaging* designs, incorporating insights gained through research with users and organizing content through information architecture.

I worked closely with developers, providing them with the tools and guidelines to elevate their work. Using JavaScript, HTML and CSS, I engaged directly in development code, ensuring that designs adhered to project requirements and aligned with business goals and user needs.

Day by Day: JavaScript, AngularJS, SASS, Sketch, Trello, Github

Web Designer

March 2012 - January 2019

Selfrules

In my role as Founder and CEO of Selfrules, I have had the opportunity to wear multiple hats. As **Web Project Manager**, **Frontend Developer and UX Designer**, I have shaped web design and development, honing my technical skills with tools such as HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, AngularJs, Node.js and Material.

As a *leader*, I played a key role in *project management*, coming up with innovative ideas, balancing projects, and providing top-notch customer support. This experience was not just a job, but a *journey of growth* and discovery, navigating the vast ocean of digital and guiding my clients and collaborators to new horizons of success.

Day by Day: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Wordpress, Photoshop, Illustrator

Products Driven

LeadsBridge

January 2021 - May 2023

LeadsBridge is a marketing automation platform that facilitates the process of synchronizing leads between an advertising platform and a CRM, improving lead management and optimizing marketing campaigns.

I hereby consent to the processing of my personal data contained in my application for the purpose of the recruitment process.

Team: 11 persone

Role: Product Owner

Company: ActiveProspect

Market: Lead Generation, Consent Based Marketing

Day by Day: Jira, Confluence, Slack

CliensPiù

October 2016 - January 2021

CliensPiù is advanced management software designed to facilitate the management and organization of professional firms, offering tools for billing, client management, scheduling and work optimization.

Team: 6 persone

Role: Ux/Ui Designer, Front-end Developer, Project Manager

Company: Giuffrè Francis Lefebvre

Market: Legale, Gestionale Studi Legali

Day by Day: SASS, Sketch, AngularJS, Github

Education

Computer Science Expert

October 2002 - June 2008

Primo Levi High School

Diploma in Computer Science, Information Technology

Master in Web Development

January 2016 - July 2016

Artoo Campus

Master in Web & Mobile Development, Web & Mobile App Development

Certified Scrum Product Owner

April 2019 - now

Scrum Alliance, Inc.

Certified ScrumMaster

May 2020 - now

Scrum Alliance, Inc.